<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><simpledc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../schemas/dc.xsd"><title>Exclusion Problems and the Cardinality of Logical Space</title><creator>Button, Tim</creator><subject>atomist picture</subject><subject>logical space</subject><subject>colour-exclusion</subject><subject>color incompatibility</subject><subject>logical independence</subject><subject>Tractarian metaphysics</subject><subject>Ludwig Wittgenstein</subject><subject>Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus</subject><subject>Sarah Moss</subject><description>This is the final version of the article. It first appeared from Springer via http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10992-016-9412-z</description><description>Wittgenstein’s atomist picture, as embodied in his Tractatus, is initially very appealing. However, it faces the famous colour-exclusion problem. In this paper, I shall explain when the atomist picture can be defended (in principle) in the face of that problem; and, in the light of this, why the atomist picture should be rejected. I outline the atomist picture in Section 1. In Section 2, I present a very simple necessary and sufficient condition for the tenability (in principle) of the atomist picture. The condition is: $\textit{logical space is a power of two}$. In Sections 3 and 4, I outline the colour-exclusion problem, and then show how the cardinality-condition supplies a response to exclusion problems. In Section 5, I explain how this amounts to a distillation of a proposal due to Moss (2012), which goes back to Carruthers (1990: 144–7). And in Section 6, I show how all this vindicates Wittgenstein’s ultimate rejection of the atomist picture. The brief reason is that we have no guarantee that there are any solutions to a given exclusion problem but, if there are any, then there are far too many.</description><description>Funded by a Philip Leverhulme Prize, awarded by the Leverhulme Trust, PLP–2014–140.</description><date>2016-10-27T09:39:03Z</date><date>2016-10-27T09:39:03Z</date><date>2016-10-04</date><type>Article</type><identifier>https://www.repository.cam.ac.uk/handle/1810/260928</identifier><identifier>10.17863/CAM.6098</identifier><language>en</language><rights>Attribution 4.0 International</rights><rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</rights><publisher>Springer</publisher></simpledc>