<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><simpledc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../schemas/dc.xsd"><title>Issues of identity and individuality in quantum mechanics</title><creator>Caulton, Adam</creator><contributor>Butterfield, Jeremy</contributor><subject>Quantum mechanics</subject><subject>Identity</subject><subject>Individuality</subject><subject>Discernibility</subject><subject>Particle</subject><subject>Entanglement</subject><description>This dissertation is ordered into three Parts. Part I is an investigation into identity, indiscernibility and individuality in logic and metaphysics.  In Chapter 2, I investigate identity and discernibility in classical first-order logic. My aim will will be to define four different ways in which objects can be discerned from one another, and to relate these definitions: (i) to the idea of symmetry; and (ii) to the idea of individuality.&#xD;
In Chapter 3, the four kinds of discernibility are put to use in defining four rival metaphysical theses about indiscernibility and individuality.&#xD;
&#xD;
Part II sets up a philosophical framework for the work of Part III.  In Chapter 4, I give an account of the rational reconstruction of concepts, inspired chiefly by Carnap and Haslanger. I also offer an account of the interpretation of physical theories.  In Chapter 5, I turn to the specific problem of finding candidate concepts of particle. I present five desiderata that any putative explication ought to satisfy, in order that the proposed concept is a concept of particle at all.&#xD;
&#xD;
Part III surveys three rival proposals for the concept of particle in quantum mechanics.  In Chapter 6, I define factorism and distinguish it from haecceitism. I then propose an amendment to recent work by Saunders, Muller and Seevinck, which seeks to show that factorist particles are all at least weakly discernible. I then present reasons for rejecting factorism.  In Chapter 7, I investigate and build on recent heterodox proposals by Ghirardi, Marinatto and Weber about the most natural concept of entanglement, and by Zanardi about the idea of a natural decomposition of an assembly.  In Chapter 8, I appraise the first of my two heterodox proposals for the concept of particle, varietism. I define varietism, and then compare its performance against the desiderata laid out in Chapter 5. I argue that, despite its many merits, varietism suffers a fatal ambiguity problem.  In Chapter 9, I present the second heterodox proposal: emergentism. I argue that emergentism provides the best concept of particle, but that it is does so imperfectly; so there may be no concept of particle to be had in quantum mechanics. If emergentism is true, then particles are (higher-order) properties of the assembly, itself treated as the basic bearer of properties.</description><description>This work was supported by the Arts and Humanities Research Council [grant number 2007/134560].</description><date>2015-07-22T15:46:03Z</date><date>2015-07-22T15:46:03Z</date><date>2015-06-30</date><type>Thesis</type><type>doctoral</type><type>PhD</type><identifier>http://www.repository.cam.ac.uk/handle/1810/249007</identifier><language>en_US</language><rights>CC0 1.0 Universal</rights><rights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</rights><publisher>University of Cambridge</publisher><publisher>Faculty of Philosophy</publisher></simpledc>