<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><simpledc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../schemas/dc.xsd"><title>Grades of Discrimination: Indiscernibility, Symmetry, and Relativity</title><creator>Button, Tim</creator><subject>Identity of Indiscernibles</subject><subject>Grades of indiscernibility</subject><subject>Grades of symmetry</subject><subject>Grades of relativity</subject><subject>Equality-free model theory</subject><subject>Identity-free model theory</subject><description>This is the author accepted manuscript. It is currently under indefinite embargo pending publication by Duke University Press.</description><description>There are several relations which may fall short of genuine identity,&#xD;
but which behave like identity in important respects. Such grades of discrimi-&#xD;
nation have recently been the subject of much philosophical and technical dis-&#xD;
cussion. This paper aims to complete their technical investigation. Grades of&#xD;
indiscernibility are defined in terms of satisfaction of certain first-order formu-&#xD;
las. Grades of symmetry are defined in terms of symmetries on a structure. Both&#xD;
of these families of grades of discrimination have been studied in some detail.&#xD;
However, this paper also introduces grades of relativity, defined in terms of rela-&#xD;
tiveness correspondences. This paper explores the relationships between all the&#xD;
grades of discrimination, exhaustively answering several natural questions that&#xD;
have so far received only partial answers. It also establishes which grades can&#xD;
be captured in terms of satisfaction of object-language formulas, and draws con-&#xD;
nections with definability theory.</description><date>2015-05-26T10:16:01Z</date><date>2015-05-26T10:16:01Z</date><date>2015</date><type>Article</type><type>accepted version</type><identifier>http://www.repository.cam.ac.uk/handle/1810/247954</identifier><language>en</language><publisher>Duke University Press</publisher></simpledc>