<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><simpledc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../schemas/dc.xsd"><title>Praise without Perfection: A Dilemma for Right-Making Reasons</title><creator>Sliwa, Paulina</creator><description>This is the author accepted manuscript. The final version is available from the University of Illinois Press via http://apq.press.illinois.edu/52/2/sliwa.html</description><description>When you don’t know what to do, you’d better find out. Sometimes the best way to find out is to ask for advice. And when you don’t know what the right thing to do is, it’s sometimes good to rely on moral advice. So much should be uncontroversial. &#xD;
&#xD;
Yet this straightforward thought spells serious trouble for a popular and widespread approach to moral worth: on this approach, agents deserve moral praise for a right action only if they are acting on right-making reasons. &#xD;
&#xD;
The first part of this paper argues that cases of moral advice present right-making reasons accounts with a dilemma: depending on how we make the right-making relation precise, we either have to deny that agents who seek out and follow moral advice are morally praiseworthy or we have to credit morally wrong actions by unsavory characters with moral worth. This casts doubt on the claim that acting on right-making reasons can be both necessary or sufficient for moral worth. &#xD;
&#xD;
The second half of the paper explores an alternative proposal: what’s required for moral worth is moral knowledge. This idea has been unpopular in recent literature. My aim is to show that it deserves serious consideration.</description><date>2016-04-01T15:29:37Z</date><date>2016-04-01T15:29:37Z</date><date>2015-04-01</date><type>Article</type><type>accepted version</type><identifier>http://apq.press.illinois.edu/52/2/sliwa.html</identifier><identifier>https://www.repository.cam.ac.uk/handle/1810/254758</identifier><language>en</language><publisher>University of Illinois Press</publisher></simpledc>