<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><simpledc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:doc="http://www.lyncode.com/xoai" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../schemas/dc.xsd"><title>Powerful qualities, the conceivability argument and the nature of the physical</title><creator>Taylor, Henry</creator><subject>powerful qualities</subject><subject>physical</subject><subject>dispositional properties</subject><subject>conceivability argument</subject><subject>ultimate argument</subject><subject>Chalmers</subject><description>This is the final version of the article. It first appeared from Springer via http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11098-016-0774-4</description><description>David Chalmers’ ‘conceivability’ argument against physicalism is perhaps the most widely discussed and controversial argument in contemporary philosophy of mind. Recently, several thinkers have suggested a novel response to this argument, which employs the ‘powerful qualities’ ontology of properties. In this paper, I argue that this response fails because it presupposes an implausible account of the physical/phenomenal distinction. In the course of establishing this, I discuss the so-called ‘ultimate’ argument for the claim that dispositional properties form the subject matter of physics. I argue that the ultimate argument can be interpreted in a strong or a weak way, and that the strong interpretation is implausible. I argue that this undermines the powerful qualities based response to the conceivability argument. I also argue for a general conclusion: that we should not define ‘the physical’ exclusively in terms of a distinction drawn from ontology.</description><description>Thanks also to the Leverhulme Trust and the Isaac Newton Trust for an Early Career Fellowship (ECF-2015-088) that provided support while the paper was being written.</description><date>2016-10-27T09:33:02Z</date><date>2016-10-27T09:33:02Z</date><date>2016-09-15</date><type>Article</type><identifier>https://www.repository.cam.ac.uk/handle/1810/260927</identifier><identifier>10.17863/CAM.6095</identifier><language>en</language><rights>Attribution 4.0 International</rights><rights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</rights><publisher>Springer</publisher></simpledc>